ABHIJEET LOKHANDE, DATA SCIENTIST/ML ENGINEER

London, United Kingdom, abl.ds@outlook.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ablds/, https://github.com/abhijeetlokhande1996

PROFILE

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer with proven experience in NLP, Geo-spatial Data Science, Large Language Models(LLM), Generative AI and Predictive Modelling. Proficient in location intelligence, Python, AWS and Data Engineering. Winner of Built-AI ML Hackathon.

SKILLS

Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Spacy, Gensim, NLP, GCP, Django, Flask, FastAPI, Python, R, XGBoost, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Pandas, Geopandas, Generative AI, MySQL, MongoDB, Machine Learning, Data Visualisation, AWS, AWS Textract, Deep Learning, Predictive Modelling, SQL, NoSQL, Data orchestration, Regression, Classification, Anomaly Detection, Keras, S3, Docker, Data Analysis, PySpark, Git, Time series forecasting, Feature Engineering.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Built AI Apr 2020 - Present

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer

London, UK

- Reduced rent per square foot error by 60% by improving the existing predictive machine learning model by developing a 3D cosine kernel.
- Improved link rate of London property databases by 30% by improving the existing linking algorithm by developing NLP model to detect various components in the UK address.
- Reduced project creation time on the Built AI platform from 55 mins to 30 mins by improving the existing NLP model by integrating AWS Textract and developing a custom integration algorithm.
- Reduced generation time of location intelligence maps by 40% by optimising the existing algorithm by integrating precomputed location grid references developed in GeoPandas.

King's College London

March 2021 - January 2022

Data Scientist London, UK

- Enhanced the novelty score of drug structure by 63% by developing a new Deep Learning model by using Graph Convolution Network and Generative Adversarial Network(GAN).
- Designed and implemented a robust data preprocessing pipeline for clinical data, ensuring accuracy and completeness of the million rows dataset.

Aspect Ratio

February 2018 - June 2020

Software Engineer - Data Science

Pune, India

- Developed web-based forecasting model for more than 100 countries to predict patient progression and revenue of a drug.
- Developed a dashboard of polished visualisations to share results of data analyses.
- Improved R2 score of regression model by 20% by improving existing machine learning model by implementing feature engineering.

EDUCATION

King's College London

September 2020 - June 2022

MSc in Data Science

London, UK

Pune University

June 2013 - June 2017

B.E. in Computer Science

Pune, India